Fetterley, Judith; Papers apap085
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Judith Fetterley Papers
1971-1993
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap085
0.5 cubic ft.
The collection includes materials related to the women's issues with a particular emphasis on the University at Albany, SUNY. Records of particular interest are those of Albany Women Against Rape, Capital District Women, and the Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY. Also included are issues of the publication The Spokeswoman (1971-1981).
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical History
Dr. Judith Fetterley was born in 1938 in New York City. Dr. Fetterly graduated with her B.A. from Swarthmore College and earned her Ph.D. in English at Indiana University in 1969. Dr. Fetterley taught at the University of Pennsylvania until 1973. She then moved to Albany and took up a position at the State University of New York at Albany where she taught English as well as women's studies. In 2004, Dr. Fetterley earned the rank of Distinguished Teaching Professor at the University.
Dr. Fetterley is known for her 1978 book, The Resisting Reader: A Feminist Approach to American Fiction. The book looks at historically famous writers such as Faulkner, Fitzgerald, and Hawthorne and how their writing "immasculated" women readers. Dr. Fetterley is also known for writing resistance books and reviews in women's literature.
After leaving academics in 2004, Dr. Fetterley became a professional gardener. She owns her own gardening design business called Perennial Wisdom.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes materials related to the women's issues with a particular emphasis on the University at Albany, SUNY. Records of particular interest are those of Albany Women Against Rape, Capital District Women, and the Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY. Also included are issues of the publication The Spokeswoman (1971-1981).
Related collections include Andrea Lurie (APAP-051), Joan Schultz (APAP-216), Gloria DeSole (APAP-215), and the Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, Albany Chapter (UA-089). Additional related collections can be found at the subject page for Women and Education.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series.
Women; Education; Albany, New York; Women's rights--New York (State); Women--Employment--New York (State); Universities and colleges--New York (State)--Faculty; Fetterley, Judith, 1938-; State University of New York at Albany
- Albany Women Against Rape, Undated (Box 1 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 1)
- Capital District Women, ca. 1972-1973 (Box 1 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 2)
- Challenge: Women in Higher Education, Summer Institutes, 1972 (Box 1 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 3)
- Course, English 590: Women in Literature, Syllabi, Exams, etc., 1976-1987 (Box 1 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 4)
- Violence Against Women, University at Albany, 1993 (Box 1 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 5)
- "Women and Tenure at Albany: A Guide for Faculty," Women's Concerns Committee, 1987 (Box 1 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 6)
- The Spokeswoman volume 1, 1971 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 1)
- The Spokeswoman volume 2, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 2)
- The Spokeswoman volume 3, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 3)
- The Spokeswoman volume 4, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 4)
- The Spokeswoman volume 5, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 5)
- The Spokeswoman volume 6, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 6)
- The Spokeswoman volume 7, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 7)
- The Spokeswoman volume 8, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 8)
- The Spokeswoman volume 9, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 9)
- The Spokeswoman volume 10, 1980 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 10)
- The Spokeswoman volume 11, 1981 (Box 2 (Judith Fetterley Papers), Folder 11)